<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Change on The Objective Perspective</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/change/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Change on The Objective Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2026 Joshua Goth All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 16:13:13 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Human Upgrade. Why Our Survival Depends on Redefining Humanity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/11/the-human-upgrade.-why-our-survival-depends-on-redefining-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 16:13:13 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/11/the-human-upgrade.-why-our-survival-depends-on-redefining-humanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;redefining-our-own-definition&#34;&gt;Redefining Our Own Definition&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I mentioned in a prior post that humanity is a double-edged sword. We have the profound ability to create, matched only by our capacity to destroy. Our darkness can be as void and deep as our brightest, shining light.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are masters of ingenuity, yet despite this, we seem unable to learn from our past mistakes. In other words, history keeps repeating itself. The single common denominator throughout the entire history of humankind is us: humans.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legacy of Greed, The Future We&#39;re Choosing Not to Build </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/11/legacy-of-greed-the-future-were-choosing-not-to-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:02:32 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/11/legacy-of-greed-the-future-were-choosing-not-to-build/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;humanity-a-double-edged-sword&#34;&gt;Humanity: A Double-Edged Sword&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Humanity is a double-edged sword. Our ingenuity goes hand-in-hand with our stupidity; of that, I am sure we can all agree. But why? Why do we choose &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to fix what is? Why do those in power consistently fail to make the choices that would better society, and instead only better themselves?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Plainly put, we have the resources to solve nearly every problem on earth, yet we &lt;strong&gt;choose&lt;/strong&gt; not to. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s merely my own personal lack of understanding, but if I were in a position of insurmountable wealth, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do everything I could to keep society down. I would focus on ensuring the survival of our species.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
