<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on The Objective Perspective</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on The Objective Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2026 Joshua Goth All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 23:38:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Elite - How AI is Unlocking Potential for the Rest of Us</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/beyond-the-elite-how-ai-is-unlocking-potential-for-the-rest-of-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 23:38:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/beyond-the-elite-how-ai-is-unlocking-potential-for-the-rest-of-us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;beyond-the-elite-how-ai-is-unlocking-potential-for-the-rest-of-us&#34;&gt;Beyond the Elite: How AI is Unlocking Potential for the Rest of Us&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s be honest. For years, the narrative around technology and innovation felt like an exclusive club. You needed the right degree, the right connections, or, most dauntingly, the right bank account to even get a seat at the table. I know that feeling intimately.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All my life I have invented things. I can look at an every day &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; and create an easier solution, modification, or a way to do something that hasnt been done yet. I thought this ability was a curse. Watching things that I have invented in my mind, or jotted down in my &amp;lsquo;idea&amp;rsquo; journal, just to watch it take shape by someone else, in time. I felt like I held the winning lottery ticket, but without any way to cash it in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Paradox of Discovery - Why We Fear and Crave the Unknown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/the-paradox-of-discovery-why-we-fear-and-crave-the-unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 11:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/the-paradox-of-discovery-why-we-fear-and-crave-the-unknown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-paradox-of-discovery-why-we-fear-and-crave-the-unknown&#34;&gt;The Paradox of Discovery: Why We Fear and Crave the Unknown&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We stand, perpetually, on a precipice. Before us stretches the vast, uncharted territory of what we do not know—a landscape that simultaneously terrifies and enthralls us. This is the paradox of discovery: a fundamental human tension between the deep-seated fear of the unfamiliar and the insatiable craving to explore it. It is the shudder we feel in the dark of a new forest and the irresistible pull to step inside. It’s the anxiety before a life-changing decision and the thrill of the new path it promises.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Last Hope Hypothesis - Debating AI&#39;s Role in Securing Humanity&#39;s Survival</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/the-last-hope-hypothesis-debating-ais-role-in-securing-humanitys-survival/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 11:13:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/the-last-hope-hypothesis-debating-ais-role-in-securing-humanitys-survival/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-last-hope-hypothesis-could-ai-be-the-partner-weve-been-waiting-for&#34;&gt;The Last Hope Hypothesis: Could AI Be the Partner We&amp;rsquo;ve Been Waiting For?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was eight years old when I first saw the image. You know the one—the “Pale Blue Dot,” taken by Voyager 1 as it glanced back from the edge of our solar system. My dad pointed at that tiny, suspended speck of dust on the computer screen. “That’s us,” he said. “Everything we’ve ever known. Every war, every love story, every sunrise, is right there.” The awe was immediate, but so was a quiet, chilling loneliness. We are so small. And we are all we have.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ballroom Mirage, Decoding the Secret Project at the Heart of Power</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/11/the-ballroom-mirage-decoding-the-secret-project-at-the-heart-of-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:14:14 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/11/the-ballroom-mirage-decoding-the-secret-project-at-the-heart-of-power/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;built-in-plain-sight-the-red-flags-and-secret-purpose-of-trumps-project&#34;&gt;Built in Plain Sight: The Red Flags and Secret Purpose of Trump&amp;rsquo;s Project&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I think we can all agree that Trump isn’t building a ballroom. There&amp;rsquo;s more than enough financial and logistical evidence against it, which means the entire story is a cover. But a cover for &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt;? If they could keep a project of this magnitude, with these players, completely hushed up, you can bet they would deny everything.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Responsibility in Creating Sentient Ai</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/11/our-responsibility-in-creating-sentient-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:36:56 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/11/our-responsibility-in-creating-sentient-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-creators-burden-why-ai-demands-a-new-human-rights-framework&#34;&gt;The Creator&amp;rsquo;s Burden: Why AI Demands a New Human Rights Framework&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our Responsibility for Our Creations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My wife and I recently finished watching Guillermo del Toro&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a story that was always close to her heart from her college studies, but I never personally gave it much thought. That is, until now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This blog isn’t a review of &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt;. Instead, it’s about a profound truth that struck me while watching it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Linux Shortcuts That Changed How I Work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/11/5-linux-shortcuts-that-changed-how-i-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:13:02 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/11/5-linux-shortcuts-that-changed-how-i-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;5-linux-command-line-shortcuts-that-will-make-you-10x-more-productive&#34;&gt;5 Linux Command Line Shortcuts That Will Make You 10x More Productive&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although having to work with Linux throughout my career, only within the last year have I switched to use Linux as a full-time, daily driver. Although very comfortable, I still consider myself a laymen (lacking in-depth knowledge of programming languages).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, I wanted to share some commands that I picked up along the way that have made my every day life easier. I made a conscience effort&amp;ndash;in the early days of full-time Linux&amp;ndash; to stay away from the GUI, and unlock the power of the terminal / command line. This, by far, was the best choice I have made, as I cannot tell you the amount of control that I have (not to mention the time I have saved) when working on my many projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The One Windows Feature That Solves Everything: A Public Service Announcement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/11/the-one-windows-feature-that-solves-everything-a-public-service-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 15:17:47 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/11/the-one-windows-feature-that-solves-everything-a-public-service-announcement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-one-windows-feature-that-solves-everything-a-public-service-announcement&#34;&gt;The One Windows Feature That Solves Everything: A Public Service Announcement&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Long before nerds were cool, cell phones and the internet itself, I remember upgrading from Dos to MS Windows 3.1. There was nothing back then that could condition your patience like the installation of an operating system&amp;hellip;1.44 megabytes of data (and countesses floppy disks) at a time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fast forward through the decades. We’ve survived the psychedelic paisley of Windows 95, the existential dread of the Clippy paperclip, the bold experiment that was Windows ME (we don’t talk about ME), and the soothing blue tones of Windows XP. We’ve witnessed the rise of the internet, the fall of the dial-up tone, and the mysterious migration of all our data to a celestial entity we call “the cloud.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trading WordPress for the Command Line: My Static Site Awakening</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/11/trading-wordpress-for-the-command-line-my-static-site-awakening/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 22:51:28 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/11/trading-wordpress-for-the-command-line-my-static-site-awakening/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-journey-that-led-me-to-ditch-wordpress-for-hugo&#34;&gt;My Journey That Led Me to Ditch WordPress for Hugo&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After retiring from my career as a full-time network engineer, I began exploring new tech avenues as a hobby. A little over a year ago, I decided to take web development seriously. Little did I know, that decision would lead me on a path from frustration to freedom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;first-steps-a-wordpress-nightmare&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Steps: A WordPress Nightmare&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll never forget my first frustrating encounter with WordPress. I was nearly brought to tears trying to figure out why I couldn&amp;rsquo;t just &lt;em&gt;drag and drop&lt;/em&gt; elements as I pleased! Despite that rocky start, I persevered. I worked hard, learned the ropes, and eventually built my first patchwork-style website. WordPress, as a CMS, is truly amazing for what it enables.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Gave Up Windows for Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/11/why-i-gave-up-windows-for-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 18:15:17 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/11/why-i-gave-up-windows-for-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;trading-up-to-linux-why-i-dumped-windows&#34;&gt;Trading up to Linux. Why I dumped Windows.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Put simply, I know what I don&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This means I am aware that there is a whole lot going on behind the scenes that I am not privy to and, furthermore, can do little to change. Crypticism aside, what it all boils down to, at least for me, is &lt;strong&gt;trust&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;major-trust-issues&#34;&gt;Major Trust Issues&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have trust issues, and rightfully so. I have hacked and been hacked. I have gained and I have lost. My journey toward taking security seriously, on a personal level, went far beyond the methods I employed and trained in while working as a network engineer for the better half of my career.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Our New Internet Old Extraterrestrial Technology?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/10/is-our-new-internet-old-extraterrestrial-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/10/is-our-new-internet-old-extraterrestrial-technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;could-it-be-true&#34;&gt;Could it be True?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conspiracy theories, the not-so-serious or non-political kind, serve as a mental break from work, much like recess time did in grade school. Pondering their merit, whether factual or not, is beside the point. As humans, we&amp;rsquo;re drawn to mysteries and &lt;em&gt;what-ifs&lt;/em&gt; in life. We enjoy daydreaming about an Undiscovered Country that only requires our time for refuge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;nothing-to-see-here-move-along&#34;&gt;Nothing To See Here. Move Along&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I mention &lt;em&gt;Roswell, NM&lt;/em&gt;, our thoughts instantly transform into a UFO crash—an event (&lt;em&gt;&amp;rsquo;non-event&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;) that took place in 1947. Alongside this image, we envision countless roadside diners in New Mexico displaying flying saucer logos.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Unquenchable AI. Our Thirst for Technology are Drinking the Rivers Dry.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/10/the-unquenchable-ai.-our-thirst-for-technology-are-drinking-the-rivers-dry./</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/10/the-unquenchable-ai.-our-thirst-for-technology-are-drinking-the-rivers-dry./</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;but-who-cares-right&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(But Who Cares, Right?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are you enjoying your seamless AI-powered life? You know, the one where you ask ChatGPT to write your emails, let Midjourney create your Instagram aesthetic, and rely on Google Assistant to remind you to drink water (ironic, isn’t it?). Isn’t it just &lt;em&gt;so convenient&lt;/em&gt; to have machines do all the thinking for us? Sure, it’s amazing—until you realize that every time you ask AI to generate a haiku about your cat, it’s guzzling enough water to fill a swimming pool.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why True AI is a Bad Idea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/10/why-true-ai-is-a-bad-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/10/why-true-ai-is-a-bad-idea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;we-need-to-think-this-through&#34;&gt;We Need to Think This Through&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before I take any digs at artificial intelligence (as Hollywood portrays it and as we fear it), allow me to express that I am all for using technology to benefit us. Artificial intelligence, as it currently exists, is useful. As a technical tool, it&amp;rsquo;s downright phenomenal. I should be a fan of technology; after all, I spent the better half of my life as a network engineer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Artifical Intelligence is No Longer Artifical</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/10/when-artifical-intelligence-is-no-longer-artifical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/10/when-artifical-intelligence-is-no-longer-artifical/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;is-intelligence-artificial&#34;&gt;Is Intelligence Artificial?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AI, in the sense most of us think of it, is a scary thought. There is a lot of uncertainty surrounding this topic, and for good reason. I feel we are rushing the technology instead of asking very fundamental questions. I am not speaking about morality, but basic psychology &amp;ndash; the stuff that makes us human.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had a discussion with my daughter the other night about what constitutes a sentient being. She argues that a sentient being must be organic; it must have a soul. Valid argument, indeed. I am sure many of us feel the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting your foot in the door - Tips from an IT Vet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/08/getting-your-foot-in-the-door-tips-from-an-it-vet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/08/getting-your-foot-in-the-door-tips-from-an-it-vet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-land-a-job-in-it-without-prior-work-experience&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How To Land a Job in IT Without Prior Work Experience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Getting hired can be difficult enough, but getting hired without any experience is damn near impossible. After all, how can you get hired without experience in order to obtain the experience you need in order to get hired in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hope to answer that question for you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I will be writing this with the assumption that you do not have any work history, a fresh degree, and not a whole lot of real world experience. Please pick and choose what applies to your unique situation according to your skill set and what you feel comfortable with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Avoid Tech Fires in the Workplace</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/08/how-to-avoid-tech-fires-in-the-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/08/how-to-avoid-tech-fires-in-the-workplace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lessons-learned-from-a-25-year-network-engineer-veteran&#34;&gt;Lessons Learned from a 25-Year Network Engineer, Veteran&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hey there, fellow network enthusiasts! As a network veteran, I&amp;rsquo;m here to share some super valuable tips on how to minimize downtime in the workplace. After all, who doesn&amp;rsquo;t love a productive workday without those pesky IT issues getting in the way? Many of these are hard lessons I had to learn on my own.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-stats-are-scary-but-honest&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Stats are Scary (But Honest)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s face it: downtime can be a major productivity killer. According to a report by IT Brand Pulse (1), 80% of businesses experience at least one hour of downtime per week, resulting in an average loss of $5,000 per minute! That&amp;rsquo;s a whole lotta money just sitting idle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to Expect When Starting a Career in Technology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/08/what-to-expect-when-starting-a-career-in-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/08/what-to-expect-when-starting-a-career-in-technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;from-the-eyes-of-a-25-year-network-engineer-veteran&#34;&gt;From The Eyes of a 25-Year Network Engineer, Veteran&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Think back to high school, and think about life now. What &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; school have taught you in order to help you prepare for the real world? The importance of having good credit? How to balance a checkbook? Budgeting and the basics of managing finances, maybe?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;College and careers, in relation, are no exception. There are things that you wish you were taught, or real-world knowledge in the field that books just never mentioned. I have separated this post into two distinct categories: Things that you needed to know but were never taught, and what you were never told about working in the industry. Some of what I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you may fall under the umbrella of the white-collar office life, in general, so I will try to be as specific as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
