<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on The Objective Perspective</title>
    <link>https://joshuagoth.com/categories/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on The Objective Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2026 Joshua Goth All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:14:14 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuagoth.com/categories/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Ballroom Mirage, Decoding the Secret Project at the Heart of Power</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/the-ballroom-mirage-decoding-the-secret-project-at-the-heart-of-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:14:14 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/the-ballroom-mirage-decoding-the-secret-project-at-the-heart-of-power/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;built-in-plain-sight-the-red-flags-and-secret-purpose-of-trumps-project&#34;&gt;Built in Plain Sight: The Red Flags and Secret Purpose of Trump&amp;rsquo;s Project&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I think we can all agree that Trump isn’t building a ballroom. There&amp;rsquo;s more than enough financial and logistical evidence against it, which means the entire story is a cover. But a cover for &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt;? If they could keep a project of this magnitude, with these players, completely hushed up, you can bet they would deny everything.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SNAP Benefit Cuts: Making Food Last</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/snap-benefit-cuts-making-food-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 20:24:37 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/snap-benefit-cuts-making-food-last/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;navigating-the-november-snap-cuts-a-survival-guide&#34;&gt;Navigating the November SNAP cuts: A Survival Guide&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There have always been two subjects I try to stay away from: religion—which I know a great deal about—and politics, something I have chosen to avoid due to the divide opinions can cause.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve kept my head in the sand, intentionally steering clear of what is happening in America, as though by some magic, I would not be affected by it. I was wrong. It is affecting me and has been for some time. Now, myself, along with 44 million other Americans who rely on SNAP assistance to feed our families, finds that November will be a very difficult month for many of us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Political Divide in America</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/10/the-political-divide-in-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/10/the-political-divide-in-america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-true-cost-of-politics-a-call-to-unite&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The True Cost of Politics: A Call to Unite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I navigate the complexities of our society, I&amp;rsquo;m compelled to acknowledge that I don&amp;rsquo;t engage in political discussions. My decision isn&amp;rsquo;t driven by a lack of interest or willingness to debate; rather, it stems from a profound understanding of politics&amp;rsquo; divisive nature. The truth is, politics can cleave even the most closely-knit relationships – families, friends, and loved ones – apart.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
