<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Parentification on The Objective Perspective</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/series/parentification/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Parentification on The Objective Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2026 Joshua Goth All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 09:54:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/series/parentification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Healing Family Dynamics - How to Talk to Your In-Laws About Their Parenting Impact</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/healing-family-dynamics-how-to-talk-to-your-in-laws-about-their-parenting-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 09:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/healing-family-dynamics-how-to-talk-to-your-in-laws-about-their-parenting-impact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;navigating-the-unspoken-a-guide-to-discussing-parenting-impact-with-in-laws&#34;&gt;Navigating the Unspoken: A Guide to Discussing Parenting Impact with In-Laws&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me begin by stating a truth many of us know intimately: you can deeply care for people while simultaneously recognizing that their actions—especially as parents—have caused profound hurt. My own in-laws are, in many respects, lovely people. They are generous with their time, offer help when they can, and undoubtedly love their family. Yet, it is an open secret within the walls of our family dynamic that their parenting has left deep, lingering wounds. Their two adult sons, my husband included for a time, found the gravitational pull of the family home impossible to escape. The household is shadowed by unaddressed anxiety, depression, and a stifling sense of arrested development. The patriarch, a man of considerable intellectual acumen, can dissect complex theories yet remains bewilderingly opaque to the emotional currents in his own living room. He is, as I’ve often thought, a case study in intellectual intelligence divorced entirely from emotional awareness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Family Comes First - Exploring the Emotional Duty to Care for Adult Siblings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/when-family-comes-first-exploring-the-emotional-duty-to-care-for-adult-siblings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 09:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/when-family-comes-first-exploring-the-emotional-duty-to-care-for-adult-siblings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;when-family-comes-first-the-unseen-weight-of-caring-for-adult-siblings&#34;&gt;When Family Comes First: The Unseen Weight of Caring for Adult Siblings&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My wife has a smile that can light up a room, a laugh that feels like home, and a heart so vast it sometimes forgets its own borders. Lately, I’ve noticed a shadow in that light, a subtle tension in her shoulders that has nothing to do with our jobs, our mortgage, or the relentless pace of modern life. It has to do with two addresses: ours, and the one where her adult brothers, both over thirty, still live.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Cycle - When Your Spouse Feels Obligated to Their Parents and Siblings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/breaking-the-cycle-when-your-spouse-feels-obligated-to-their-parents-and-siblings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 08:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/breaking-the-cycle-when-your-spouse-feels-obligated-to-their-parents-and-siblings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;breaking-the-cycle-when-your-spouse-feels-obligated-to-their-parents-and-siblings&#34;&gt;Breaking the Cycle: When Your Spouse Feels Obligated to Their Parents and Siblings&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hey there. Let’s talk about something that doesn’t get enough airtime in the “happy marriage” playbook: what happens when your partner’s sense of duty to their family of origin starts feeling like a third wheel in your relationship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You know the scene. A planned date night gets canceled for a last-minute sibling crisis. A significant chunk of your savings is quietly redirected to help a parent, without a conversation. You feel like you’re constantly competing for your spouse’s attention, and the competitors are their mom, dad, brother, or sister. It’s not that they don’t love you—it’s that an invisible, powerful sense of &lt;strong&gt;obligation&lt;/strong&gt; is calling the shots.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Parentified Spouse, How Childhood Roles Can Reshape Your Marriage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/the-parentified-spouse-how-childhood-roles-can-reshape-your-marriage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 23:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/the-parentified-spouse-how-childhood-roles-can-reshape-your-marriage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-parentified-spouse-how-childhood-roles-can-reshape-your-marriage&#34;&gt;The Parentified Spouse: How Childhood Roles Can Reshape Your Marriage&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever felt like you’re the only adult in the room, even when your partner is right beside you? Do you find yourself managing the household, the emotions, and the logistics of your marriage with a sense of weary responsibility that feels older than your years? If so, you might be experiencing the echoes of a childhood role known as &lt;strong&gt;parentification&lt;/strong&gt;, and its impact on your marriage could be more profound than you realize.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Love Birds. A Story, by Joshua M. Goth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/the-love-birds.-a-story-by-joshua-m.-goth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/the-love-birds.-a-story-by-joshua-m.-goth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-price-of-love&#34;&gt;The Price of Love&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am going to kick off a series that may hit home for a lot of folks. Its about the damage that too much love can cause your child in the long run. Like any story that I am hit with, this woke me up at 4:30 in the morning after a night of meditating about my in-laws, and the damage that being an over-protective parent can do. Like many, I am doing all I can to keep a pair of adult men who were never taught how to care for themselves from showing up at my door in their early 40&amp;rsquo;s, looking for a place to live. But my frustration doesnt compare the the amount of suffering that my wife is enduring. Like any supportive spouse, I know that in order to help, I need to understand, so allow me to share what I have learned in this series in hopes it can help you, as well. . . But first, a story. . .&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
