<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on The Objective Perspective</title>
    <link>https://joshuagoth.com/categories/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on The Objective Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2026 Joshua Goth All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:19:45 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuagoth.com/categories/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Happiness and the Currency of the Soul</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/happiness-and-the-currency-of-the-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:19:45 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/happiness-and-the-currency-of-the-soul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-alchemist--the-simple-power-of-a-great-book&#34;&gt;The Alchemist &amp;amp; The Simple Power of a Great Book&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are all kinds of books in the world. Good books, bad books, and those we simply forget. But every now and then, if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky, you find a book so profound it doesn&amp;rsquo;t just change your life—it reveals the answers to questions you&amp;rsquo;ve been carrying within you all along.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paulo Coelho&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Alchemist&lt;/em&gt; is that kind of book. It&amp;rsquo;s a short read, barely 180 pages, but I urge you to treat it like all precious things: take your time. Savor it. Ingest its messages slowly and deliberately.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Human Upgrade. Why Our Survival Depends on Redefining Humanity</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/the-human-upgrade.-why-our-survival-depends-on-redefining-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 16:13:13 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/the-human-upgrade.-why-our-survival-depends-on-redefining-humanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;redefining-our-own-definition&#34;&gt;Redefining Our Own Definition&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I mentioned in a prior post that humanity is a double-edged sword. We have the profound ability to create, matched only by our capacity to destroy. Our darkness can be as void and deep as our brightest, shining light.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are masters of ingenuity, yet despite this, we seem unable to learn from our past mistakes. In other words, history keeps repeating itself. The single common denominator throughout the entire history of humankind is us: humans.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legacy of Greed, The Future We&#39;re Choosing Not to Build </title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/legacy-of-greed-the-future-were-choosing-not-to-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:02:32 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/legacy-of-greed-the-future-were-choosing-not-to-build/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;humanity-a-double-edged-sword&#34;&gt;Humanity: A Double-Edged Sword&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Humanity is a double-edged sword. Our ingenuity goes hand-in-hand with our stupidity; of that, I am sure we can all agree. But why? Why do we choose &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to fix what is? Why do those in power consistently fail to make the choices that would better society, and instead only better themselves?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Plainly put, we have the resources to solve nearly every problem on earth, yet we &lt;strong&gt;choose&lt;/strong&gt; not to. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s merely my own personal lack of understanding, but if I were in a position of insurmountable wealth, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do everything I could to keep society down. I would focus on ensuring the survival of our species.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Saticlysm Philosophy. A Simple Way of Living</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/10/the-saticlysm-philosophy.-a-simple-way-of-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/10/the-saticlysm-philosophy.-a-simple-way-of-living/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#Changing Your World and The World Around You&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am not reinventing the wheel, nor am I rebranding centuries of historical&amp;ndash;and agreed upon&amp;ndash; truths. All I am doing is simply acknowledging that it is there. Being mindful of existence, gives life to it. Makes the immaterial - matter. By knowing we have a place in history is like picking up a pencil midway in life in order to document, and pay attention to it. &amp;ndash; It has always been, but now, we are able to see it. To watch it grow, take shape and alter the world around ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
