<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Help on The Objective Perspective</title>
    <link>https://joshuagoth.com/tags/help/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Help on The Objective Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2026 Joshua Goth All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 18:18:52 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuagoth.com/tags/help/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Buy Me a Coffee</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/buy-me-a-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 18:18:52 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/buy-me-a-coffee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;hello-everyone&#34;&gt;Hello, everyone!&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A quick and honest note from me today. I’m working on growing this blog&amp;rsquo;s reach, and am thrilled with things I plan to add and to do in order to help and entertain. The most powerful way you can help is, of course by sharing. If you read a post that resonates with you or think it could help a friend or loved one, please pass it along. Sharing these posts is the best way to help increase traffic which will, in turn, aid to keep my blog online.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Financial Help. Resources for When Times Are Tough</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/navigating-financial-help.-resources-for-when-times-are-tough/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 01:59:05 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/navigating-financial-help.-resources-for-when-times-are-tough/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;navigating-financial-help-resources-for-when-times-are-tough&#34;&gt;Navigating Financial Help: Resources for When Times Are Tough&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Everyone needs a little help from time to time. Some people need ongoing support, while others just need a temporary boost to get back on their feet. No matter your situation, there are programs designed to help.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post highlights benefits available in Washington State. However, a quick search shows that most states offer similar services. It&amp;rsquo;s always worth checking what&amp;rsquo;s available in your local area!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Failing Words - How Self-Harm Becomes a Teen’s Only Voice</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/10/failing-words-how-self-harm-becomes-a-teens-only-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/10/failing-words-how-self-harm-becomes-a-teens-only-voice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;understanding-self-harm-35-years-later&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding Self-Harm: 35 Years Later&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the age of 12 until 23, I self-mutilated almost daily. I don’t know how I learned it—or if I even &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; learn it. And though, at the time, I thought I knew why, I never truly understood it. Until now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I write here comes from experience and insight—a deeper understanding that arrived after years of avoidance, when I wasn’t searching for it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The power of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a&#xA;  href=&#34;https://joshuagoth.com/learning-to-be-mindful/&#34;&#xA;  &#xA;  &gt;using meditation as a tool for self-discovery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; cannot be overstated. Meditation is peculiar; sometimes, you focus on solving one problem, only for a forgotten memory—buried for years—to surface unexpectedly. These revelations are priceless, life-altering, and come &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; when you’re ready to understand them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Devistating and Long-Term Effects of Being Homeless</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/08/the-devistating-and-long-term-effects-of-being-homeless/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/08/the-devistating-and-long-term-effects-of-being-homeless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-know-firsthand-what-it-is-like-to-be-without-a-home&#34;&gt;I Know Firsthand, What it is Like to Be Without a Home&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Homelessness is more than just the absence of a physical shelter; it&amp;rsquo;s a profound disruption to one&amp;rsquo;s sense of security, identity, and belonging. The psychological toll it exacts can be devastating, and the longer one remains without a home, the deeper these mental wounds can become.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have found myself without a home more times than I care to write about. One of my earliest childhood memories was my mother bathing me in a sink at a homeless shelter, and within the last few years, alone in a ruined vehicle without a back window during one of the worst winters I have seen.The long term effects of being homeless are devistating. However, with proper support you can help recover from many traumas that homelessness can inflict.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
