<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marriage on The Objective Perspective</title>
    <link>https://joshuagoth.com/tags/marriage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Marriage on The Objective Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2026 Joshua Goth All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 09:23:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuagoth.com/tags/marriage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>When Family Comes First - Exploring the Emotional Duty to Care for Adult Siblings</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2026/01/when-family-comes-first-exploring-the-emotional-duty-to-care-for-adult-siblings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 09:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2026/01/when-family-comes-first-exploring-the-emotional-duty-to-care-for-adult-siblings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;when-family-comes-first-the-unseen-weight-of-caring-for-adult-siblings&#34;&gt;When Family Comes First: The Unseen Weight of Caring for Adult Siblings&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My wife has a smile that can light up a room, a laugh that feels like home, and a heart so vast it sometimes forgets its own borders. Lately, I’ve noticed a shadow in that light, a subtle tension in her shoulders that has nothing to do with our jobs, our mortgage, or the relentless pace of modern life. It has to do with two addresses: ours, and the one where her adult brothers, both over thirty, still live.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Cycle - When Your Spouse Feels Obligated to Their Parents and Siblings</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2026/01/breaking-the-cycle-when-your-spouse-feels-obligated-to-their-parents-and-siblings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 08:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2026/01/breaking-the-cycle-when-your-spouse-feels-obligated-to-their-parents-and-siblings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;breaking-the-cycle-when-your-spouse-feels-obligated-to-their-parents-and-siblings&#34;&gt;Breaking the Cycle: When Your Spouse Feels Obligated to Their Parents and Siblings&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hey there. Let’s talk about something that doesn’t get enough airtime in the “happy marriage” playbook: what happens when your partner’s sense of duty to their family of origin starts feeling like a third wheel in your relationship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You know the scene. A planned date night gets canceled for a last-minute sibling crisis. A significant chunk of your savings is quietly redirected to help a parent, without a conversation. You feel like you’re constantly competing for your spouse’s attention, and the competitors are their mom, dad, brother, or sister. It’s not that they don’t love you—it’s that an invisible, powerful sense of &lt;strong&gt;obligation&lt;/strong&gt; is calling the shots.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Parentified Spouse, How Childhood Roles Can Reshape Your Marriage</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2026/01/the-parentified-spouse-how-childhood-roles-can-reshape-your-marriage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 23:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2026/01/the-parentified-spouse-how-childhood-roles-can-reshape-your-marriage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-parentified-spouse-how-childhood-roles-can-reshape-your-marriage&#34;&gt;The Parentified Spouse: How Childhood Roles Can Reshape Your Marriage&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever felt like you’re the only adult in the room, even when your partner is right beside you? Do you find yourself managing the household, the emotions, and the logistics of your marriage with a sense of weary responsibility that feels older than your years? If so, you might be experiencing the echoes of a childhood role known as &lt;strong&gt;parentification&lt;/strong&gt;, and its impact on your marriage could be more profound than you realize.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
