<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Power on The Objective Perspective</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/power/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Power on The Objective Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2026 Joshua Goth All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 23:38:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/power/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Elite - How AI is Unlocking Potential for the Rest of Us</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/beyond-the-elite-how-ai-is-unlocking-potential-for-the-rest-of-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 23:38:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/beyond-the-elite-how-ai-is-unlocking-potential-for-the-rest-of-us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;beyond-the-elite-how-ai-is-unlocking-potential-for-the-rest-of-us&#34;&gt;Beyond the Elite: How AI is Unlocking Potential for the Rest of Us&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s be honest. For years, the narrative around technology and innovation felt like an exclusive club. You needed the right degree, the right connections, or, most dauntingly, the right bank account to even get a seat at the table. I know that feeling intimately.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All my life I have invented things. I can look at an every day &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; and create an easier solution, modification, or a way to do something that hasnt been done yet. I thought this ability was a curse. Watching things that I have invented in my mind, or jotted down in my &amp;lsquo;idea&amp;rsquo; journal, just to watch it take shape by someone else, in time. I felt like I held the winning lottery ticket, but without any way to cash it in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happiness and the Currency of the Soul</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/11/happiness-and-the-currency-of-the-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:19:45 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/11/happiness-and-the-currency-of-the-soul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-alchemist--the-simple-power-of-a-great-book&#34;&gt;The Alchemist &amp;amp; The Simple Power of a Great Book&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are all kinds of books in the world. Good books, bad books, and those we simply forget. But every now and then, if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky, you find a book so profound it doesn&amp;rsquo;t just change your life—it reveals the answers to questions you&amp;rsquo;ve been carrying within you all along.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paulo Coelho&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Alchemist&lt;/em&gt; is that kind of book. It&amp;rsquo;s a short read, barely 180 pages, but I urge you to treat it like all precious things: take your time. Savor it. Ingest its messages slowly and deliberately.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
