<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Parenting on The Objective Perspective</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/parenting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Parenting on The Objective Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2026 Joshua Goth All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 09:54:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/parenting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Healing Family Dynamics - How to Talk to Your In-Laws About Their Parenting Impact</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/healing-family-dynamics-how-to-talk-to-your-in-laws-about-their-parenting-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 09:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/healing-family-dynamics-how-to-talk-to-your-in-laws-about-their-parenting-impact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;navigating-the-unspoken-a-guide-to-discussing-parenting-impact-with-in-laws&#34;&gt;Navigating the Unspoken: A Guide to Discussing Parenting Impact with In-Laws&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me begin by stating a truth many of us know intimately: you can deeply care for people while simultaneously recognizing that their actions—especially as parents—have caused profound hurt. My own in-laws are, in many respects, lovely people. They are generous with their time, offer help when they can, and undoubtedly love their family. Yet, it is an open secret within the walls of our family dynamic that their parenting has left deep, lingering wounds. Their two adult sons, my husband included for a time, found the gravitational pull of the family home impossible to escape. The household is shadowed by unaddressed anxiety, depression, and a stifling sense of arrested development. The patriarch, a man of considerable intellectual acumen, can dissect complex theories yet remains bewilderingly opaque to the emotional currents in his own living room. He is, as I’ve often thought, a case study in intellectual intelligence divorced entirely from emotional awareness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Mindfulness Puts You on The Path to Become a Great Parent</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/10/how-mindfulness-puts-you-on-the-path-to-become-a-great-parent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/10/how-mindfulness-puts-you-on-the-path-to-become-a-great-parent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;every-moment-matters&#34;&gt;Every Moment Matters&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a parent, it can be overwhelming to navigate the ups and downs of raising your little ones. As parents, we don’t need added difficulties in the department of raising children, so those that suffer from mental health problems are fighting another battle altogether. More often than not, it’s not only the parent who suffers, but also the child (and this is where the cycle of abuse / violence./ neglect continues—or is born).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
