<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Family on The Objective Perspective</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/family/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Family on The Objective Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2026 Joshua Goth All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 09:23:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>When Family Comes First - Exploring the Emotional Duty to Care for Adult Siblings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/when-family-comes-first-exploring-the-emotional-duty-to-care-for-adult-siblings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 09:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/when-family-comes-first-exploring-the-emotional-duty-to-care-for-adult-siblings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;when-family-comes-first-the-unseen-weight-of-caring-for-adult-siblings&#34;&gt;When Family Comes First: The Unseen Weight of Caring for Adult Siblings&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My wife has a smile that can light up a room, a laugh that feels like home, and a heart so vast it sometimes forgets its own borders. Lately, I’ve noticed a shadow in that light, a subtle tension in her shoulders that has nothing to do with our jobs, our mortgage, or the relentless pace of modern life. It has to do with two addresses: ours, and the one where her adult brothers, both over thirty, still live.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Cycle - When Your Spouse Feels Obligated to Their Parents and Siblings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/breaking-the-cycle-when-your-spouse-feels-obligated-to-their-parents-and-siblings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 08:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/breaking-the-cycle-when-your-spouse-feels-obligated-to-their-parents-and-siblings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;breaking-the-cycle-when-your-spouse-feels-obligated-to-their-parents-and-siblings&#34;&gt;Breaking the Cycle: When Your Spouse Feels Obligated to Their Parents and Siblings&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hey there. Let’s talk about something that doesn’t get enough airtime in the “happy marriage” playbook: what happens when your partner’s sense of duty to their family of origin starts feeling like a third wheel in your relationship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You know the scene. A planned date night gets canceled for a last-minute sibling crisis. A significant chunk of your savings is quietly redirected to help a parent, without a conversation. You feel like you’re constantly competing for your spouse’s attention, and the competitors are their mom, dad, brother, or sister. It’s not that they don’t love you—it’s that an invisible, powerful sense of &lt;strong&gt;obligation&lt;/strong&gt; is calling the shots.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Love Birds. A Story, by Joshua M. Goth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/the-love-birds.-a-story-by-joshua-m.-goth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/the-love-birds.-a-story-by-joshua-m.-goth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-price-of-love&#34;&gt;The Price of Love&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am going to kick off a series that may hit home for a lot of folks. Its about the damage that too much love can cause your child in the long run. Like any story that I am hit with, this woke me up at 4:30 in the morning after a night of meditating about my in-laws, and the damage that being an over-protective parent can do. Like many, I am doing all I can to keep a pair of adult men who were never taught how to care for themselves from showing up at my door in their early 40&amp;rsquo;s, looking for a place to live. But my frustration doesnt compare the the amount of suffering that my wife is enduring. Like any supportive spouse, I know that in order to help, I need to understand, so allow me to share what I have learned in this series in hopes it can help you, as well. . . But first, a story. . .&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Difficult Family Members Shut Down Upon Hearing the Truth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/08/why-difficult-family-members-shut-down-upon-hearing-the-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/08/why-difficult-family-members-shut-down-upon-hearing-the-truth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;family-drama---episode-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Family Drama - Episode 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like most people, I have trouble with my in-laws. Of course, everyone&amp;rsquo;s situation is different, and therefore how we approach each situation is equally different. But for those of you who, like me, have an in-law (or parent) who refuses to listen, shuts down the moment the truth comes out, or just defies reality altogether, and have tried, for years, in every possible way to communicate; don&amp;rsquo;t throw in the towel just yet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Proven Methods on How To Communicate With Impossible Family Members</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/08/10-proven-methods-on-how-to-communicate-with-impossible-family-members/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/08/10-proven-methods-on-how-to-communicate-with-impossible-family-members/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;family-drama---episode-2&#34;&gt;Family Drama - Episode 2&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cracking the Code&lt;/strong&gt;. In an earlier blog, I discussed some common reasons why difficult family members shut down when you attempt to communicate with them, and explode when approached with the truth about themselves. In Part 2, I now discuss proven psychological methods and examples on how to safely approach them in order to effectively communicate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Apply the Truth-Telling Principles With Shut-Down Family Members&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
