<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internet on The Objective Perspective</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/internet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internet on The Objective Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2026 Joshua Goth All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 15:17:47 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/internet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The One Windows Feature That Solves Everything: A Public Service Announcement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/11/the-one-windows-feature-that-solves-everything-a-public-service-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 15:17:47 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/11/the-one-windows-feature-that-solves-everything-a-public-service-announcement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-one-windows-feature-that-solves-everything-a-public-service-announcement&#34;&gt;The One Windows Feature That Solves Everything: A Public Service Announcement&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Long before nerds were cool, cell phones and the internet itself, I remember upgrading from Dos to MS Windows 3.1. There was nothing back then that could condition your patience like the installation of an operating system&amp;hellip;1.44 megabytes of data (and countesses floppy disks) at a time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fast forward through the decades. We’ve survived the psychedelic paisley of Windows 95, the existential dread of the Clippy paperclip, the bold experiment that was Windows ME (we don’t talk about ME), and the soothing blue tones of Windows XP. We’ve witnessed the rise of the internet, the fall of the dial-up tone, and the mysterious migration of all our data to a celestial entity we call “the cloud.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Our New Internet Old Extraterrestrial Technology?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/10/is-our-new-internet-old-extraterrestrial-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/10/is-our-new-internet-old-extraterrestrial-technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;could-it-be-true&#34;&gt;Could it be True?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conspiracy theories, the not-so-serious or non-political kind, serve as a mental break from work, much like recess time did in grade school. Pondering their merit, whether factual or not, is beside the point. As humans, we&amp;rsquo;re drawn to mysteries and &lt;em&gt;what-ifs&lt;/em&gt; in life. We enjoy daydreaming about an Undiscovered Country that only requires our time for refuge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;nothing-to-see-here-move-along&#34;&gt;Nothing To See Here. Move Along&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I mention &lt;em&gt;Roswell, NM&lt;/em&gt;, our thoughts instantly transform into a UFO crash—an event (&lt;em&gt;&amp;rsquo;non-event&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;) that took place in 1947. Alongside this image, we envision countless roadside diners in New Mexico displaying flying saucer logos.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
