<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mindful on The Objective Perspective</title>
    <link>https://joshuagoth.com/tags/mindful/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mindful on The Objective Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2026 Joshua Goth All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:19:45 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuagoth.com/tags/mindful/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Happiness and the Currency of the Soul</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/happiness-and-the-currency-of-the-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:19:45 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/happiness-and-the-currency-of-the-soul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-alchemist--the-simple-power-of-a-great-book&#34;&gt;The Alchemist &amp;amp; The Simple Power of a Great Book&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are all kinds of books in the world. Good books, bad books, and those we simply forget. But every now and then, if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky, you find a book so profound it doesn&amp;rsquo;t just change your life—it reveals the answers to questions you&amp;rsquo;ve been carrying within you all along.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paulo Coelho&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Alchemist&lt;/em&gt; is that kind of book. It&amp;rsquo;s a short read, barely 180 pages, but I urge you to treat it like all precious things: take your time. Savor it. Ingest its messages slowly and deliberately.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Mindfulness Puts You on The Path to Become a Great Parent</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/10/how-mindfulness-puts-you-on-the-path-to-become-a-great-parent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/10/how-mindfulness-puts-you-on-the-path-to-become-a-great-parent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;every-moment-matters&#34;&gt;Every Moment Matters&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a parent, it can be overwhelming to navigate the ups and downs of raising your little ones. As parents, we don’t need added difficulties in the department of raising children, so those that suffer from mental health problems are fighting another battle altogether. More often than not, it’s not only the parent who suffers, but also the child (and this is where the cycle of abuse / violence./ neglect continues—or is born).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Saticlysm Philosophy. A Simple Way of Living</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/10/the-saticlysm-philosophy.-a-simple-way-of-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/10/the-saticlysm-philosophy.-a-simple-way-of-living/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#Changing Your World and The World Around You&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am not reinventing the wheel, nor am I rebranding centuries of historical&amp;ndash;and agreed upon&amp;ndash; truths. All I am doing is simply acknowledging that it is there. Being mindful of existence, gives life to it. Makes the immaterial - matter. By knowing we have a place in history is like picking up a pencil midway in life in order to document, and pay attention to it. &amp;ndash; It has always been, but now, we are able to see it. To watch it grow, take shape and alter the world around ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming Mindful. Choosing the Path to a Better Life</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/07/becoming-mindful.-choosing-the-path-to-a-better-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/07/becoming-mindful.-choosing-the-path-to-a-better-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#The Path to Mindfulness and the Power of Change&#xA;Mindfulness is an extraordinary ability, bordering on the supernatural. Practicing mindfulness is akin to an intense mental workout at the gym, but instead of building physical strength, it enhances your mental capacities. Imagine having the power to regulate your heart rate, blood pressure, moods, perspectives, and interactions with people just by focusing your thoughts. This guide does not focus on wishing things into existence (although I encourage spreading positive energies for everyone), but rather provides a crash course in exercises designed to help you cultivate a stronger mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
