<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thought Trot on The Objective Perspective</title>
    <link>https://joshuagoth.com/categories/thought-trot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thought Trot on The Objective Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2026 Joshua Goth All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:14:14 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuagoth.com/categories/thought-trot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Ballroom Mirage, Decoding the Secret Project at the Heart of Power</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/the-ballroom-mirage-decoding-the-secret-project-at-the-heart-of-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:14:14 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/the-ballroom-mirage-decoding-the-secret-project-at-the-heart-of-power/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;built-in-plain-sight-the-red-flags-and-secret-purpose-of-trumps-project&#34;&gt;Built in Plain Sight: The Red Flags and Secret Purpose of Trump&amp;rsquo;s Project&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I think we can all agree that Trump isn’t building a ballroom. There&amp;rsquo;s more than enough financial and logistical evidence against it, which means the entire story is a cover. But a cover for &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt;? If they could keep a project of this magnitude, with these players, completely hushed up, you can bet they would deny everything.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geek Bar vs. Geek Boost, An Honest Review of the Vape Doppelgänger</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/geek-bar-vs.-geek-boost-an-honest-review-of-the-vape-doppelg%C3%A4nger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:39:23 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/geek-bar-vs.-geek-boost-an-honest-review-of-the-vape-doppelg%C3%A4nger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;geek-bar-vs-geek-boost-more-than-just-a-knockoff&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geek Bar vs. Geek Boost: More Than Just a Knockoff?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I vape. It’s one of my last remaining vices. Let&amp;rsquo;s be clear, it&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em&gt;healthy&lt;/em&gt;, but I figure it’s a step up from smoking or, you know, inhaling tremendous amounts of narcotics. I’m writing this because I had a realization about what might be happening behind the scenes in the vape world, and I wanted to share the differences between two brands you might encounter: &lt;strong&gt;Geek Bar&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Geek Boost&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Responsibility in Creating Sentient Ai</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/our-responsibility-in-creating-sentient-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:36:56 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/our-responsibility-in-creating-sentient-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-creators-burden-why-ai-demands-a-new-human-rights-framework&#34;&gt;The Creator&amp;rsquo;s Burden: Why AI Demands a New Human Rights Framework&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our Responsibility for Our Creations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My wife and I recently finished watching Guillermo del Toro&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a story that was always close to her heart from her college studies, but I never personally gave it much thought. That is, until now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This blog isn’t a review of &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt;. Instead, it’s about a profound truth that struck me while watching it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Our New Internet Old Extraterrestrial Technology?</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/10/is-our-new-internet-old-extraterrestrial-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/10/is-our-new-internet-old-extraterrestrial-technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;could-it-be-true&#34;&gt;Could it be True?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conspiracy theories, the not-so-serious or non-political kind, serve as a mental break from work, much like recess time did in grade school. Pondering their merit, whether factual or not, is beside the point. As humans, we&amp;rsquo;re drawn to mysteries and &lt;em&gt;what-ifs&lt;/em&gt; in life. We enjoy daydreaming about an Undiscovered Country that only requires our time for refuge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;nothing-to-see-here-move-along&#34;&gt;Nothing To See Here. Move Along&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I mention &lt;em&gt;Roswell, NM&lt;/em&gt;, our thoughts instantly transform into a UFO crash—an event (&lt;em&gt;&amp;rsquo;non-event&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;) that took place in 1947. Alongside this image, we envision countless roadside diners in New Mexico displaying flying saucer logos.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What it Means to Dream</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/08/what-it-means-to-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/08/what-it-means-to-dream/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-possibilities-of-dreams&#34;&gt;The Possibilities of Dreams&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I could rehash scientific theories until I am blue in the face, but that is not what this post is about. Instead, I would like to share my thoughts and experiences on dreams.Since a life altering event during a time of homelessness in 2021, I have experienced dreams differently than I had before. I rarely have dreams of which I consider are my own (meaning people, events and setting are familiar). I no longer dream of my life. The events that transpire in my dreams happen in another time and place. The languages of each dream are of a tongue I have never heard, but do understand. The technologies are oftentimes nearly impossible to discribe, as though the place where I am, at the time, does not follow the laws of physics as we know them today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
