<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Health on The Objective Perspective</title>
    <link>https://joshuagoth.com/tags/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health on The Objective Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2026 Joshua Goth All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 23:06:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuagoth.com/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Parentified Spouse, How Childhood Roles Can Reshape Your Marriage</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2026/01/the-parentified-spouse-how-childhood-roles-can-reshape-your-marriage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 23:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2026/01/the-parentified-spouse-how-childhood-roles-can-reshape-your-marriage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-parentified-spouse-how-childhood-roles-can-reshape-your-marriage&#34;&gt;The Parentified Spouse: How Childhood Roles Can Reshape Your Marriage&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever felt like you’re the only adult in the room, even when your partner is right beside you? Do you find yourself managing the household, the emotions, and the logistics of your marriage with a sense of weary responsibility that feels older than your years? If so, you might be experiencing the echoes of a childhood role known as &lt;strong&gt;parentification&lt;/strong&gt;, and its impact on your marriage could be more profound than you realize.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming Mindful. Choosing the Path to a Better Life</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/07/becoming-mindful.-choosing-the-path-to-a-better-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/07/becoming-mindful.-choosing-the-path-to-a-better-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#The Path to Mindfulness and the Power of Change&#xA;Mindfulness is an extraordinary ability, bordering on the supernatural. Practicing mindfulness is akin to an intense mental workout at the gym, but instead of building physical strength, it enhances your mental capacities. Imagine having the power to regulate your heart rate, blood pressure, moods, perspectives, and interactions with people just by focusing your thoughts. This guide does not focus on wishing things into existence (although I encourage spreading positive energies for everyone), but rather provides a crash course in exercises designed to help you cultivate a stronger mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
