<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mental Health on The Objective Perspective</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/mental-health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mental Health on The Objective Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2026 Joshua Goth All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 23:06:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/mental-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Parentified Spouse, How Childhood Roles Can Reshape Your Marriage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/the-parentified-spouse-how-childhood-roles-can-reshape-your-marriage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 23:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/the-parentified-spouse-how-childhood-roles-can-reshape-your-marriage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-parentified-spouse-how-childhood-roles-can-reshape-your-marriage&#34;&gt;The Parentified Spouse: How Childhood Roles Can Reshape Your Marriage&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever felt like you’re the only adult in the room, even when your partner is right beside you? Do you find yourself managing the household, the emotions, and the logistics of your marriage with a sense of weary responsibility that feels older than your years? If so, you might be experiencing the echoes of a childhood role known as &lt;strong&gt;parentification&lt;/strong&gt;, and its impact on your marriage could be more profound than you realize.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gentle Art of Crafting a New Year&#39;s Resolution</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/the-gentle-art-of-crafting-a-new-years-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/the-gentle-art-of-crafting-a-new-years-resolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;forget-the-grand-gestures-the-gentle-art-of-crafting-a-new-years-resolution-that-actually-sticks&#34;&gt;Forget the Grand Gestures: The Gentle Art of Crafting a New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolution That Actually Sticks&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s be honest. How many of us have spent December 31st in a flurry of champagne-fueled optimism, scribbling down a list of life-altering goals, only to find that list—slightly crumpled and filled with guilt—by mid-February? I’ve got a drawer full of them. “Run a marathon.” “Learn fluent Italian.” “Become a morning person who also meditates and bakes their own sourdough.” By January 15th, I’d be exhausted, disappointed, and reaching for the takeout menu, convinced I’d already failed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Love Birds. A Story, by Joshua M. Goth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/the-love-birds.-a-story-by-joshua-m.-goth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2026/01/the-love-birds.-a-story-by-joshua-m.-goth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-price-of-love&#34;&gt;The Price of Love&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am going to kick off a series that may hit home for a lot of folks. Its about the damage that too much love can cause your child in the long run. Like any story that I am hit with, this woke me up at 4:30 in the morning after a night of meditating about my in-laws, and the damage that being an over-protective parent can do. Like many, I am doing all I can to keep a pair of adult men who were never taught how to care for themselves from showing up at my door in their early 40&amp;rsquo;s, looking for a place to live. But my frustration doesnt compare the the amount of suffering that my wife is enduring. Like any supportive spouse, I know that in order to help, I need to understand, so allow me to share what I have learned in this series in hopes it can help you, as well. . . But first, a story. . .&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changing Our Views on Success .</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/10/changing-our-views-on-success-./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/10/changing-our-views-on-success-./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#Learning to See What Truly Matters in Life&#xA;As I&amp;rsquo;ve emphasized before, nearly everything in life is subjective, and our concept of success is no exception. So, what does success mean? If you asked 100 different people about their idea of success, you&amp;rsquo;d likely get 100 distinct answers. For many, success is merely a reflection of one&amp;rsquo;s personal dreams or ultimate goals in life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Success can also be viewed through multiple lenses. What I mean by that is, success can be seen as an overall achievement, as well as individual accomplishments. A person may excel in companionship but struggle in other areas, yet still be considered successful as a parent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Failing Words - How Self-Harm Becomes a Teen’s Only Voice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/10/failing-words-how-self-harm-becomes-a-teens-only-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/10/failing-words-how-self-harm-becomes-a-teens-only-voice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;understanding-self-harm-35-years-later&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding Self-Harm: 35 Years Later&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the age of 12 until 23, I self-mutilated almost daily. I don’t know how I learned it—or if I even &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; learn it. And though, at the time, I thought I knew why, I never truly understood it. Until now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I write here comes from experience and insight—a deeper understanding that arrived after years of avoidance, when I wasn’t searching for it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The power of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a&#xA;  href=&#34;https://joshuagoth.com/learning-to-be-mindful/&#34;&#xA;  &#xA;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;using meditation as a tool for self-discovery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; cannot be overstated. Meditation is peculiar; sometimes, you focus on solving one problem, only for a forgotten memory—buried for years—to surface unexpectedly. These revelations are priceless, life-altering, and come &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; when you’re ready to understand them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Courage to Admit Mistakes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/10/the-courage-to-admit-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/10/the-courage-to-admit-mistakes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-owning-up-matters&#34;&gt;Why &lt;em&gt;Owning-Up&lt;/em&gt; Matters&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever found yourself quick to shift blame when things go wrong? I&amp;rsquo;m no exception. But often, we see mistakes as a reflection of our own worthiness – and that&amp;rsquo;s a problem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the thing about mistakes – they might not feel like it at first, but they can actually be turning points for growth and learning. If only we can see them as chances to improve, rather than just failures to avoid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Devistating and Long-Term Effects of Being Homeless</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/08/the-devistating-and-long-term-effects-of-being-homeless/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/08/the-devistating-and-long-term-effects-of-being-homeless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-know-firsthand-what-it-is-like-to-be-without-a-home&#34;&gt;I Know Firsthand, What it is Like to Be Without a Home&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Homelessness is more than just the absence of a physical shelter; it&amp;rsquo;s a profound disruption to one&amp;rsquo;s sense of security, identity, and belonging. The psychological toll it exacts can be devastating, and the longer one remains without a home, the deeper these mental wounds can become.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have found myself without a home more times than I care to write about. One of my earliest childhood memories was my mother bathing me in a sink at a homeless shelter, and within the last few years, alone in a ruined vehicle without a back window during one of the worst winters I have seen.The long term effects of being homeless are devistating. However, with proper support you can help recover from many traumas that homelessness can inflict.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming Mindful. Choosing the Path to a Better Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/07/becoming-mindful.-choosing-the-path-to-a-better-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025/07/becoming-mindful.-choosing-the-path-to-a-better-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#The Path to Mindfulness and the Power of Change&#xA;Mindfulness is an extraordinary ability, bordering on the supernatural. Practicing mindfulness is akin to an intense mental workout at the gym, but instead of building physical strength, it enhances your mental capacities. Imagine having the power to regulate your heart rate, blood pressure, moods, perspectives, and interactions with people just by focusing your thoughts. This guide does not focus on wishing things into existence (although I encourage spreading positive energies for everyone), but rather provides a crash course in exercises designed to help you cultivate a stronger mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
