<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Survival Series on The Objective Perspective</title>
    <link>https://joshuagoth.com/series/survival-series/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Survival Series on The Objective Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2026 Joshua Goth All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 01:59:05 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuagoth.com/series/survival-series/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Financial Help. Resources for When Times Are Tough</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/navigating-financial-help.-resources-for-when-times-are-tough/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 01:59:05 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/navigating-financial-help.-resources-for-when-times-are-tough/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;navigating-financial-help-resources-for-when-times-are-tough&#34;&gt;Navigating Financial Help: Resources for When Times Are Tough&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Everyone needs a little help from time to time. Some people need ongoing support, while others just need a temporary boost to get back on their feet. No matter your situation, there are programs designed to help.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post highlights benefits available in Washington State. However, a quick search shows that most states offer similar services. It&amp;rsquo;s always worth checking what&amp;rsquo;s available in your local area!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SNAP Benefit Cuts: Making Food Last</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/snap-benefit-cuts-making-food-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 20:24:37 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/snap-benefit-cuts-making-food-last/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;navigating-the-november-snap-cuts-a-survival-guide&#34;&gt;Navigating the November SNAP cuts: A Survival Guide&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There have always been two subjects I try to stay away from: religion—which I know a great deal about—and politics, something I have chosen to avoid due to the divide opinions can cause.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve kept my head in the sand, intentionally steering clear of what is happening in America, as though by some magic, I would not be affected by it. I was wrong. It is affecting me and has been for some time. Now, myself, along with 44 million other Americans who rely on SNAP assistance to feed our families, finds that November will be a very difficult month for many of us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
