<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web on The Objective Perspective</title>
    <link>https://joshuagoth.com/tags/web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web on The Objective Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2026 Joshua Goth All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 18:18:52 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuagoth.com/tags/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Buy Me a Coffee</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/buy-me-a-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 18:18:52 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/buy-me-a-coffee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;hello-everyone&#34;&gt;Hello, everyone!&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A quick and honest note from me today. I’m working on growing this blog&amp;rsquo;s reach, and am thrilled with things I plan to add and to do in order to help and entertain. The most powerful way you can help is, of course by sharing. If you read a post that resonates with you or think it could help a friend or loved one, please pass it along. Sharing these posts is the best way to help increase traffic which will, in turn, aid to keep my blog online.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trading WordPress for the Command Line: My Static Site Awakening</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/trading-wordpress-for-the-command-line-my-static-site-awakening/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 22:51:28 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/trading-wordpress-for-the-command-line-my-static-site-awakening/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-journey-that-led-me-to-ditch-wordpress-for-hugo&#34;&gt;My Journey That Led Me to Ditch WordPress for Hugo&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After retiring from my career as a full-time network engineer, I began exploring new tech avenues as a hobby. A little over a year ago, I decided to take web development seriously. Little did I know, that decision would lead me on a path from frustration to freedom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;first-steps-a-wordpress-nightmare&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Steps: A WordPress Nightmare&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll never forget my first frustrating encounter with WordPress. I was nearly brought to tears trying to figure out why I couldn&amp;rsquo;t just &lt;em&gt;drag and drop&lt;/em&gt; elements as I pleased! Despite that rocky start, I persevered. I worked hard, learned the ropes, and eventually built my first patchwork-style website. WordPress, as a CMS, is truly amazing for what it enables.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
