<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Self-Help on The Objective Perspective</title>
    <link>https://joshuagoth.com/categories/self-help/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Self-Help on The Objective Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2026 Joshua Goth All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 18:18:52 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuagoth.com/categories/self-help/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Buy Me a Coffee</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/buy-me-a-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 18:18:52 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/buy-me-a-coffee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;hello-everyone&#34;&gt;Hello, everyone!&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A quick and honest note from me today. I’m working on growing this blog&amp;rsquo;s reach, and am thrilled with things I plan to add and to do in order to help and entertain. The most powerful way you can help is, of course by sharing. If you read a post that resonates with you or think it could help a friend or loved one, please pass it along. Sharing these posts is the best way to help increase traffic which will, in turn, aid to keep my blog online.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happiness and the Currency of the Soul</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/happiness-and-the-currency-of-the-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:19:45 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/happiness-and-the-currency-of-the-soul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-alchemist--the-simple-power-of-a-great-book&#34;&gt;The Alchemist &amp;amp; The Simple Power of a Great Book&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are all kinds of books in the world. Good books, bad books, and those we simply forget. But every now and then, if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky, you find a book so profound it doesn&amp;rsquo;t just change your life—it reveals the answers to questions you&amp;rsquo;ve been carrying within you all along.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paulo Coelho&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Alchemist&lt;/em&gt; is that kind of book. It&amp;rsquo;s a short read, barely 180 pages, but I urge you to treat it like all precious things: take your time. Savor it. Ingest its messages slowly and deliberately.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legacy of Greed, The Future We&#39;re Choosing Not to Build </title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/legacy-of-greed-the-future-were-choosing-not-to-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:02:32 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/legacy-of-greed-the-future-were-choosing-not-to-build/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;humanity-a-double-edged-sword&#34;&gt;Humanity: A Double-Edged Sword&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Humanity is a double-edged sword. Our ingenuity goes hand-in-hand with our stupidity; of that, I am sure we can all agree. But why? Why do we choose &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to fix what is? Why do those in power consistently fail to make the choices that would better society, and instead only better themselves?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Plainly put, we have the resources to solve nearly every problem on earth, yet we &lt;strong&gt;choose&lt;/strong&gt; not to. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s merely my own personal lack of understanding, but if I were in a position of insurmountable wealth, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do everything I could to keep society down. I would focus on ensuring the survival of our species.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impossible Cure: How I Unlocked My Body&#39;s Power to Heal Itself</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/the-impossible-cure-how-i-unlocked-my-bodys-power-to-heal-itself/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:40:37 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/the-impossible-cure-how-i-unlocked-my-bodys-power-to-heal-itself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-bodys-secret-the-unlikely-technique-that-healed-what-doctors-couldnt&#34;&gt;My Body&amp;rsquo;s Secret: The Unlikely Technique That Healed What Doctors Couldn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Late last year I was diagnosed with Upper and Lower Spinal Stenosis. For those of you unfamiliar with this condition, it essentially means that the sockets in between the bones in my spine have worn down and the vertebrae are grinding against one another.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like normal wear and tear on an aged automobile, this is a condition that many people suffer from. The only issue that I had with this, was that it is usually diagnosed in the elderly, ages 80+. Put simply, I have put far too many miles on this engine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Myth of Easy Times: Why We&#39;re Always Preparing for a Storm</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/the-myth-of-easy-times-why-were-always-preparing-for-a-storm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:25:38 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/the-myth-of-easy-times-why-were-always-preparing-for-a-storm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;minimizing-hardships-what-tough-times-really-mean&#34;&gt;Minimizing Hardships: What Tough Times Really Mean&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have all said it, and I feel the majority of us know what difficult times are—or do we?&#xA;Why must we always prepare ourselves &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; difficult times to come? What are we really conditioning ourselves for?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;ask-yourself-have-times-ever-truly-been-easy&#34;&gt;Ask yourself: Have Times Ever Truly Been Easy?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Speaking for myself, I am unable to recall any time in my life that was genuinely easy. Of course, looking back, I can identify periods that were &lt;em&gt;easier&lt;/em&gt; than others, but were any of those times truly &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Failing Words - How Self-Harm Becomes a Teen’s Only Voice</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/10/failing-words-how-self-harm-becomes-a-teens-only-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/10/failing-words-how-self-harm-becomes-a-teens-only-voice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;understanding-self-harm-35-years-later&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding Self-Harm: 35 Years Later&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the age of 12 until 23, I self-mutilated almost daily. I don’t know how I learned it—or if I even &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; learn it. And though, at the time, I thought I knew why, I never truly understood it. Until now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I write here comes from experience and insight—a deeper understanding that arrived after years of avoidance, when I wasn’t searching for it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The power of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a&#xA;  href=&#34;https://joshuagoth.com/learning-to-be-mindful/&#34;&#xA;  &#xA;  &gt;using meditation as a tool for self-discovery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; cannot be overstated. Meditation is peculiar; sometimes, you focus on solving one problem, only for a forgotten memory—buried for years—to surface unexpectedly. These revelations are priceless, life-altering, and come &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; when you’re ready to understand them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Manage Depression &amp; Lead a Happy Life</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/09/how-to-manage-depression-lead-a-happy-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/09/how-to-manage-depression-lead-a-happy-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;living-with-depression-part-1&#34;&gt;Living &lt;em&gt;With&lt;/em&gt; Depression (Part 1)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First and foremost: I&amp;rsquo;d like to begin by stating that if you are in danger of hurting yourself or others, please call the Crisis Lifeline at 988 (@988lifeline) for help. I am not a medical professional, and my advice should not be considered a substitute for professional assistance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those of you visiting, I&amp;rsquo;m sure that I don&amp;rsquo;t need to tell you about the horrifying nature of depression. But for those who have not experienced it, let me assure you that it is not just sadness; it is so much more, and far worse. Put simply, depression can be described as an incurable cancer of the mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Manage Depression &amp; Lead a Happy Life, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/09/how-to-manage-depression-lead-a-happy-life-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/09/how-to-manage-depression-lead-a-happy-life-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;living-with-depression-part-2&#34;&gt;Living &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; Depression (Part 2)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the first part of this series, I discussed methods that have helped me in my personal journey to manage depression. In this part, I will focus on ways that loved ones and caregivers can support those who suffer from depression.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I could compile a lengthy list of things not to do when someone you love is experiencing a depressive episode based on my own experiences with less-than-understanding partners. However, I believe it&amp;rsquo;s more beneficial to focus on the positives. Here are some methods that have proven helpful for those supporting someone with depression:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Stay Positive While Living with Chronic Pain</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/09/how-to-stay-positive-while-living-with-chronic-pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/09/how-to-stay-positive-while-living-with-chronic-pain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;title-finding-light-in-the-darkness-how-to-stay-positive-while-living-with-chronic-pain&#34;&gt;Title: Finding Light in the Darkness: How to Stay Positive While Living with Chronic Pain&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I thought my battle was over&lt;/strong&gt;. After winning a 43-year battle with depression, I hoped the worst was behind me. However, I forgot about my age. Earlier this year, I was diagnosed with something that my 82-year-old Father-In-Law was diagnosed with, and had surgery for last year; Spinal Stenosis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am no spring chicken, but I hoped I would have another 40 years before something like this hit me. To say the least, it has been painful, and even more so with dealing with our healthcare system (In my opinion, health care should not be a private, for-profit entity).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting your foot in the door - Tips from an IT Vet</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/08/getting-your-foot-in-the-door-tips-from-an-it-vet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/08/getting-your-foot-in-the-door-tips-from-an-it-vet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-land-a-job-in-it-without-prior-work-experience&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How To Land a Job in IT Without Prior Work Experience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Getting hired can be difficult enough, but getting hired without any experience is damn near impossible. After all, how can you get hired without experience in order to obtain the experience you need in order to get hired in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hope to answer that question for you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I will be writing this with the assumption that you do not have any work history, a fresh degree, and not a whole lot of real world experience. Please pick and choose what applies to your unique situation according to your skill set and what you feel comfortable with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Avoid Tech Fires in the Workplace</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/08/how-to-avoid-tech-fires-in-the-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/08/how-to-avoid-tech-fires-in-the-workplace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lessons-learned-from-a-25-year-network-engineer-veteran&#34;&gt;Lessons Learned from a 25-Year Network Engineer, Veteran&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hey there, fellow network enthusiasts! As a network veteran, I&amp;rsquo;m here to share some super valuable tips on how to minimize downtime in the workplace. After all, who doesn&amp;rsquo;t love a productive workday without those pesky IT issues getting in the way? Many of these are hard lessons I had to learn on my own.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-stats-are-scary-but-honest&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Stats are Scary (But Honest)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s face it: downtime can be a major productivity killer. According to a report by IT Brand Pulse (1), 80% of businesses experience at least one hour of downtime per week, resulting in an average loss of $5,000 per minute! That&amp;rsquo;s a whole lotta money just sitting idle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Devistating and Long-Term Effects of Being Homeless</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/08/the-devistating-and-long-term-effects-of-being-homeless/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/08/the-devistating-and-long-term-effects-of-being-homeless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-know-firsthand-what-it-is-like-to-be-without-a-home&#34;&gt;I Know Firsthand, What it is Like to Be Without a Home&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Homelessness is more than just the absence of a physical shelter; it&amp;rsquo;s a profound disruption to one&amp;rsquo;s sense of security, identity, and belonging. The psychological toll it exacts can be devastating, and the longer one remains without a home, the deeper these mental wounds can become.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have found myself without a home more times than I care to write about. One of my earliest childhood memories was my mother bathing me in a sink at a homeless shelter, and within the last few years, alone in a ruined vehicle without a back window during one of the worst winters I have seen.The long term effects of being homeless are devistating. However, with proper support you can help recover from many traumas that homelessness can inflict.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Difficult Family Members Shut Down Upon Hearing the Truth</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/08/why-difficult-family-members-shut-down-upon-hearing-the-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/08/why-difficult-family-members-shut-down-upon-hearing-the-truth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;family-drama---episode-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Family Drama - Episode 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like most people, I have trouble with my in-laws. Of course, everyone&amp;rsquo;s situation is different, and therefore how we approach each situation is equally different. But for those of you who, like me, have an in-law (or parent) who refuses to listen, shuts down the moment the truth comes out, or just defies reality altogether, and have tried, for years, in every possible way to communicate; don&amp;rsquo;t throw in the towel just yet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Proven Methods on How To Communicate With Impossible Family Members</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/08/10-proven-methods-on-how-to-communicate-with-impossible-family-members/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/08/10-proven-methods-on-how-to-communicate-with-impossible-family-members/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;family-drama---episode-2&#34;&gt;Family Drama - Episode 2&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cracking the Code&lt;/strong&gt;. In an earlier blog, I discussed some common reasons why difficult family members shut down when you attempt to communicate with them, and explode when approached with the truth about themselves. In Part 2, I now discuss proven psychological methods and examples on how to safely approach them in order to effectively communicate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Apply the Truth-Telling Principles With Shut-Down Family Members&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming Mindful. Choosing the Path to a Better Life</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/07/becoming-mindful.-choosing-the-path-to-a-better-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/07/becoming-mindful.-choosing-the-path-to-a-better-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#The Path to Mindfulness and the Power of Change&#xA;Mindfulness is an extraordinary ability, bordering on the supernatural. Practicing mindfulness is akin to an intense mental workout at the gym, but instead of building physical strength, it enhances your mental capacities. Imagine having the power to regulate your heart rate, blood pressure, moods, perspectives, and interactions with people just by focusing your thoughts. This guide does not focus on wishing things into existence (although I encourage spreading positive energies for everyone), but rather provides a crash course in exercises designed to help you cultivate a stronger mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
