<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nes on The Objective Perspective</title>
    <link>https://joshuagoth.com/tags/nes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nes on The Objective Perspective</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2026 Joshua Goth All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:17:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuagoth.com/tags/nes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Your Free Retro Arcade Awaits - Play Classic Games Instantly</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2026/01/your-free-retro-arcade-awaits-play-classic-games-instantly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:17:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2026/01/your-free-retro-arcade-awaits-play-classic-games-instantly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;your-free-retro-arcade-awaits-play-classic-games-instantly&#34;&gt;Your Free Retro Arcade Awaits: Play Classic Games Instantly&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hey there! Remember the thrill of dropping a quarter into a massive arcade cabinet, the hum of the monitor, and the satisfying &lt;em&gt;click-clack&lt;/em&gt; of the joystick? What if I told you that entire feeling—the classics, the nostalgia, the pure, unadulterated fun—is now just a click away, completely free?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, grab your virtual tokens, because I’ve built a little digital playground just for us. Welcome to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a&#xA;  href=&#34;https://arcade.joshuag.com&#34;&#xA;  &#xA;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://arcade.joshuagoth.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s my passion project: a simple, no-fuss website where you can dive straight into a library of classic games and play them instantly in your browser. No downloads (unless you want to!), no complicated setups, no credit cards. Just you, your browser, and a treasure trove of retro goodness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Nintendo Gaming Project Coming Soon</title>
      <link>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/new-nintendo-gaming-project-coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 02:53:45 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuagoth.com/blog/2025/11/new-nintendo-gaming-project-coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-love-affair-with-nintendo-is-becoming-a-new-project&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Love Affair with Nintendo is Becoming a New Project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that I have been a huge fan of Nintendo since I was about nine or ten years old. It all started on a Christmas morning back in 1988. I had just come home from the ER the day before after my first serious brush with death, and that morning, I unwrapped my first Nintendo Entertainment System. Call it what you will; Addiction or brain Damage, but from that moment on, there was simply no turning back. That gray box wasn&amp;rsquo;t just a toy; it was a portal to something that, like many others, helped shaped some of my childhood and the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
